Raunak Kathuria

Head Of IT Development

Location Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Website https://raunakkathuria.github.io/blog
Phone +60-11-2311-4190 GitHub https://github.com/raunakkathuria

Email raunakkathuria@gmail.com LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/raunakkathuria

SUMMARY

Responsible, result-oriented, and open-minded technical manager with 13+ years of total experience, including 5+ years experience in leading diverse engineering teams to accomplish business goals. Believes in servant leadership; good listener, value others' perspective, and keep team goals above personal goals. Improved team processes and workflows to increase delivery by 20%.

SOFT SKILLS

Problem-solving, Result-oriented, Team management, Servant leadership, Empathetic, Flexible, Team Collaboration, Time management, Effective Communication

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Perl, Node.js, Web socket, Docker, API, Java, JavaScript, Git, Programming, Agile

EXPERIENCE

Deriv Group Services, Malaysia - Head Of IT Development

February 2013 - Present

2021 - Present, Head Of IT Development

- Created a road-map for the team in alignment with the company road-map to achieve organizational goals.
- Managed, mentored, and led the development team to deliver products, features, and functionality on time.
- Worked collaboratively with many teams, including front-end, Operations, and QA.
- Worked with the copy writing team to create the job description to improve the hiring.

2019 - 2021, Back-end Manger

- Created an inclusive and fun working culture in the team to increase engagement.
- Mentored and groomed team leads to manage the sub-teams.
- Led to 200% increase in team size together with team leads.
- Interviewed prospective team members.

- Implemented scrum workflow that led to 20% increase in performance of the team.
- Introduced a dedicated on-boarding process for new members for standard and consistent mentoring.
- Conducted one-on-ones for performance evaluation, and to plan for the career growth of the team members.

2013 - 2017, Senior Software Engineer

- Completed more than 15 important projects within timelines.
- Developed our cryptocurrency cashier to support cryptocurrency payments for our platform.
- Separated front-end and back-end by developing a Web socket based API.

Amdocs, India - Senior Subject-Matter Expert

July 2011 - January 2013

- Designed and developed modules to enhance the functionality.
- Provided production and QA support.
- Automated workflow by creating scripts for the repeated tasks.

AON Hewitt Associates, India - Software Engineer

June 2010 - July 2011

Oracle Financial Services Software, India - Associate Consultant

August 2008 - June 2010

EDUCATION

Career Institute of Technology and Management, India - Bachelor of Engineering

August 2004 - May 2008

Computer Science

Maharshi Dayanand University

Haryana, India

CERTIFICATIONS

OKR Certification

Redis Labs | RU101: Introduction to Redis Data Structures

Redis Labs | RU202: Redis Streams

New Manager Course

Sun Certified Java Programmer (Java 1.5)